<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lom:lom xmlns:lom="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM"><lom:educational><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:description><lom:difficulty><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>medium</lom:value></lom:difficulty><lom:intendedEndUserRole/><lom:interactivityLevel><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>very low</lom:value></lom:interactivityLevel><lom:interactivityType/><lom:learningResourceType/><lom:semanticDensity/><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:educational><lom:general><lom:aggregationLevel><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>2</lom:value></lom:aggregationLevel><lom:coverage><lom:string language="en-US">united-states</lom:string></lom:coverage><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">"MentorNet received a grant from the Engineering Information Foundation to analyze data collected as part of MentorNets annual evaluation of its e-mentoring program for women in engineering and science. The purpose of the data analysis was to identify possible differences in experiences of and benefits from e-mentoring for women of color participating in MentorNets program. Data sets from the 2001  2002 and 2002  2003 academic years were the basis for the study: the sample included United States citizens only.

Statistically significant differences in the needs, experiences and perceived benefits were found for African American, Asian American, Hispanic/Latina and Caucasian students and mentors. African American students especially, but also Asian American and Hispanic/Latina students wanted a mentor to discuss issues of race/ethnicity with them; however, there were very few same-race matches and Caucasian mentors felt less comfortable than women of color in discussing such issues. From some students perspective, this is a critical need that remains unmet. In contrast, student satisfaction with e-mentoring was not related to race or to whether a student was in a same-race or cross-race match. In fact, students of color were more positive than Caucasian women about the range of MentorNet features that supplement one-on-one ementoring. They were more a part of MentorNets virtual community. 

Students of color directly attributed to MentorNet both increased motivation to succeed in their field of study and the fact that they get through the academic year. The difference between students of color and Caucasian students on these two variables was statistically significant. Written comments volunteered by students illustrate how important it was to them to have their e-mentor cheering them on from the sidelines as well as providing strategies for learning, time management and other factors that enabled students to persist in their major. E-mentors volunteer to communicate with students and aside from the gratification they feel in helping students, they also identify benefits for themselves. 

E-mentors of color were more apt to experience a number of benefits, significantly more so than Caucasian e-mentors. The most dramatic difference was with the e-mentors own increased self-confidence. Also significant were

improved supervisory skills, improved skills for recruiting new talent, better networking skills for making contacts with others, renewed commitment to their field, insight into what its like to be a student today, the opportunity to pass along what they have learned and reflection about their own career. There is a tendency in this study for some e-mentors, especially Hispanic/Latinas, to be newer to the workforce and possibly this is a major reason they improved their supervisory and recruitment skills. Future research should examine this more closely using measures that tap multiple reasons for benefits to accrue for some e-mentors more than others, so the relative import of each can be analyzed."</lom:string></lom:description><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>01C33929-168E-40FF-8EBF-EFC31041EE42</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:keyword><lom:string language="en-US">Mentor, e-mentoring, mentoring program, women, African American, Hispanic, Latina, virtual community, increase motivation, increase self-confidence, research, quantitative-small scale, intervention</lom:string></lom:keyword><lom:structure><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>hierarchical</lom:value></lom:structure><lom:title><lom:string language="en-US">E-Mentoring for women of color in engineering and science: Final report to the engineering information foundation</lom:string></lom:title><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:general><lom:lifeCycle><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:17F7360C-76EC-4BE0-8BBD-36D6FA0CAFAB
N:null;null;null;;
FN:MentorNet
ORG:http://www.mentornet.net
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>author</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2004-04-01</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:version><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:version></lom:lifeCycle><lom:metaMetadata><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:A95A4292-7E83-4C47-AC38-612313409FAE
N:Amanda Walton;;;;
FN:Amanda Walton
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>creator</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2008-02-17</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>01C33929-168E-40FF-8EBF-EFC31041EE42</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:language>en-US</lom:language><lom:metadataSchema>LOMv1.0</lom:metadataSchema></lom:metaMetadata><lom:rights><lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:cost><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:cost></lom:rights><lom:technical><lom:format/><lom:installationRemarks><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:installationRemarks><lom:location>http://www.mentornet.net/files/WomenofColorFinalReportMay2004.pdf</lom:location><lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:size>0</lom:size></lom:technical></lom:lom>