<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lom:lom xmlns:lom="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM"><lom:educational><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:description><lom:difficulty/><lom:intendedEndUserRole/><lom:interactivityLevel/><lom:interactivityType/><lom:learningResourceType/><lom:semanticDensity/><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:educational><lom:general><lom:aggregationLevel><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>2</lom:value></lom:aggregationLevel><lom:coverage><lom:string language="en-US">united-states</lom:string></lom:coverage><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">"This is a companion volume to Shaping the Future: New Expectations for
Undergraduate Education in Science, Mathematics, Engineering, and Technology
(NSF 96-139), the 1996 report of the Advisory Committee on Undergraduate
Education to the National Science Foundation's Directorate for Education and
Human Resources.  For this supplement, we have selected the materials that
helped to initiate the discussion and debate of the review, and provided the
framework for the Recommendations presented in the first volume of  Shaping the
Future.

No single document could purport to fully represent the breadth and depth of the
expansive and complicated endeavor of higher education and its reform.  While
the EHR Advisory Committee did a formidable job of soliciting broad-based
community opinion, synthesizing the issues facing contemporary undergraduate
education, and summarizing this process in its report to NSF, the material
presented in this second volume provides an essential resource for anyone
wishing to explore these issues more completely, without the benefit of
interpretation or distillation.  To this end, we have made every effort to allow
these authors to express their views in their own words and present references
and data without undue editorial revision or comment.

The review of undergraduate education and the Shaping the Future report have
already generated much discussion and activity in the U.S. education community.
In recognition of this, the National Science Foundation has initiated its
"NextSteps in Shaping the Future" campaign to capitalize upon this enthusiasm,
coordinate regional efforts, and help guide discussion towards a national
movement to achieve even greater excellence in higher education.  We begin this
volume with a summary of these ongoing, follow-up activities.

Section II of this volume presents a detailed account of NSF programs in
undergraduate education since NSB 86-100, Undergraduate Science, Mathematics and
Engineering Education: Role for the National Science Foundation and
Recommendations for Action by Other Sectors to Strengthen Collegiate Education
and Pursue Excellence in the Next Generation of U.S. Leadership in Science and
Technology, the last substantive review of undergraduate education in this
nation.  Section III presents the written remarks contributed as part of the
public hearings on undergraduate education held in October and November, 1995,
as well as an overview of the Social Sciences workshop held in February, 1996.
Section IV summarizes the series of national focus groups conducted by NSF in
1995 and 1996, while Section V presents data from a variety of sources that
contributed many-but certainly not all-essential facets to the overall analysis."</lom:string></lom:description><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>D6ABCBC3-6BB5-4049-82F1-466B55E1DB90</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:keyword><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:keyword><lom:structure><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>hierarchical</lom:value></lom:structure><lom:title><lom:string language="en-US">Shaping the Future, Volume II: Perspectives on Undergraduate Education in Science, Mathematics, Engineering, and Technology</lom:string></lom:title><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:general><lom:lifeCycle><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:628CE316-03B0-499C-9859-504C44AB77ED
N:NSF;National Science Foundation;null;;
FN:National Science Foundation NSF
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>author</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>1998-01-01</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:version><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:version></lom:lifeCycle><lom:metaMetadata><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:B0BF444F-C039-4252-BEFF-C0B6321C7418
N:Alice Agogino;;;;
FN:Alice Agogino
ADR;TYPE=work,postal,parcel:;;5136 Etcheverry HallUniversity of California at Berkeley;Berkeley;CA;;
TEL;TYPE=work,voice:510-849-0931
TEL;TYPE=work,fax:510-849-1822
PHOTO;VALUE=uri:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/agogino_shadow.gif
URL:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/index.html
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>creator</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2007-01-20</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>D6ABCBC3-6BB5-4049-82F1-466B55E1DB90</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:language>en-US</lom:language><lom:metadataSchema>LOMv1.0</lom:metadataSchema></lom:metaMetadata><lom:rights><lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:cost><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:cost></lom:rights><lom:technical><lom:format/><lom:installationRemarks><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:installationRemarks><lom:location>http://www.nsf.gov/pubs/1998/nsf98128/nsf98128.htm</lom:location><lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:size>0</lom:size></lom:technical></lom:lom>