<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lom:lom xmlns:lom="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM"><lom:educational><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:description><lom:difficulty/><lom:intendedEndUserRole/><lom:interactivityLevel/><lom:interactivityType/><lom:learningResourceType/><lom:semanticDensity/><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:educational><lom:general><lom:aggregationLevel><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>2</lom:value></lom:aggregationLevel><lom:coverage><lom:string language="en-US">united-states</lom:string></lom:coverage><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">Abstract:
"This report describes research into gender and educational background and its relationship with computer
self-efficacy and perceptions of Computer Science amongst university students and school students
in South Africa. It is important to understand these issues in the specific cultural and economic
environment of South Africa.
The main focus of this report is on self-efficacy which is defined as the beliefs an individual has
about their ability to complete certain tasks. The Cassidy and Eachus scale is used to measure general
computer self-efficacy, and course-specific self-efficacy was measured by statements describing
achievement in the course.
Amongst first year Computer Science university students, male students had significantly higher
self-efficacy than female students and predicted higher marks, but there was no difference in their
actual marks.
Amongst secondary school students no significant gender differences were found in general computer
self-efficacy. For boys, there was no link between plans to take computing at school and selfefficacy.
For girls, those who had decided to take computing had higher self-efficacy.
Students with a disadvantaged educational background were found to have mixed self-efficacy
beliefs. They had lower general computer self-efficacy than students with an advantaged educational
background, and higher course-specific self-efficacy and mark prediction. However, their actual
marks were lower.
Appendices to the report describe additional research. University students without prior experience
of programming had lower self-efficacy, lower predicted marks and lower actual marks than
those with prior programming experience. Women with no prior experience had particularly low
general computer self-efficacy beliefs.
School students with higher usage of computers had higher self-efficacy. Boys had higher computer
usage than girls. Boys perceived Computer Science as less male-oriented than girls. There was
no link between perceptions of male-orientedness and plans to study computing at school."</lom:string></lom:description><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>9F4AE205-E029-42E4-9C94-74FE912B407D</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:keyword><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:keyword><lom:structure><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>hierarchical</lom:value></lom:structure><lom:title><lom:string language="en-US">Gender and educational background and their effect on computer self-efficacy and perceptions</lom:string></lom:title><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:general><lom:lifeCycle><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:013AB44E-5AD3-4ACF-A993-CF2D60BB54F6
N:School of Computer Science, University of the Witwatersrand;Vashti Galpin, Ian Sanders, Heather Turner, Bernadine Venter;null;;
FN:Vashti Galpin, Ian Sanders, Heather Turner, Bernadine Venter School of Computer Science, University of the Witwatersrand
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>author</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2003-04-01</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:version><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:version></lom:lifeCycle><lom:metaMetadata><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:B0BF444F-C039-4252-BEFF-C0B6321C7418
N:Alice Agogino;;;;
FN:Alice Agogino
ADR;TYPE=work,postal,parcel:;;5136 Etcheverry HallUniversity of California at Berkeley;Berkeley;CA;;
TEL;TYPE=work,voice:510-849-0931
TEL;TYPE=work,fax:510-849-1822
PHOTO;VALUE=uri:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/agogino_shadow.gif
URL:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/index.html
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>creator</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2007-03-02</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>9F4AE205-E029-42E4-9C94-74FE912B407D</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:language>en-US</lom:language><lom:metadataSchema>LOMv1.0</lom:metadataSchema></lom:metaMetadata><lom:rights><lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:cost><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:cost></lom:rights><lom:technical><lom:format/><lom:installationRemarks><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:installationRemarks><lom:location>http://citeseer.ist.psu.edu/619720.html</lom:location><lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:size>0</lom:size></lom:technical></lom:lom>