<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lom:lom xmlns:lom="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM"><lom:educational><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:description><lom:difficulty/><lom:intendedEndUserRole/><lom:interactivityLevel/><lom:interactivityType/><lom:learningResourceType/><lom:semanticDensity/><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:educational><lom:general><lom:aggregationLevel><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>2</lom:value></lom:aggregationLevel><lom:coverage><lom:string language="en-US">united-states</lom:string></lom:coverage><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">Website for Kansas State's undergraduate program links to a PDF file of their new curricular program as of 2006. The general program desciption is: 
"The objective of the five year Architectural Engineering program at Kansas State University is to prepare the student with fundamental engineering competence in the analysis and design of buildings and their systems. Specifically, the student must be able to understand and apply engineering fundamentals and design principles for engineering the infrastructure of architecture- that infrastructure being structural, mechanical and electrical building systems and all the subdisciplines that are related to these primary designations. Additionally, the program provides graduates with a broad based education which will help prepare them to meet the challenges and opportunities of life in general. Architectural engineers are concerned with the task of combining the various building systems provided by today's advanced technology into an integrated whole.

The traditional method of designing a building involves the architect interviewing the client and interpreting his/her needs in the form of a building.  On the architect's part, this means determining the size and shape of the building, room sizes and relationships, traffic flow, orientation of the building on the site, and aesthetics.  When this process is complete and the client agrees with the architect that this is what he/she wants, the architect calls on consulting engineers to do the structural, mechanical, plumbing, and lighting/electrical design for the building.  In some cases, an acoustical specialist is also required.  The engineering design for the building is what architectural engineers do.

At Kansas State University, the aim of the Architectural Engineering (ARE) curriculum is to prepare entry-level engineers for the consulting engineering field who are well-grounded in the engineering specialities, but who also have an understanding of how the building is designed and built and how the engineering systems fit into the building.

To accomplish this goal, we utilize a five-year curriculum.  Essentially, this involves approximately four years of engineering and one year of building architectural and construction related courses.

Architectural engineering at Kansas State University is a five year program that integrates an Accreditation Board for Engineering Technology (ABET) engineering program with building systems courses.  This course of study provides the theoretical tools required for engineering design and the ability to apply these tools to architectural structures to provide a completely functional building."</lom:string></lom:description><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>FCA0E9E3-22DF-4415-B607-F4FA9DB55E2C</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:keyword><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:keyword><lom:structure><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>hierarchical</lom:value></lom:structure><lom:title><lom:string language="en-US">Bachelor of Science in Architectural Engineering Undergraduate Curriculum - Kansas State</lom:string></lom:title><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:general><lom:lifeCycle><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:C3853FC1-C78A-4440-9A19-3DB8F3350015
N:Kennesaw State University;Architectural Engineering and Construction Science;null;;
FN:Architectural Engineering and Construction Science Kennesaw State University
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>author</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2006-08-01</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:version><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:version></lom:lifeCycle><lom:metaMetadata><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:B0BF444F-C039-4252-BEFF-C0B6321C7418
N:Alice Agogino;;;;
FN:Alice Agogino
ADR;TYPE=work,postal,parcel:;;5136 Etcheverry HallUniversity of California at Berkeley;Berkeley;CA;;
TEL;TYPE=work,voice:510-849-0931
TEL;TYPE=work,fax:510-849-1822
PHOTO;VALUE=uri:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/agogino_shadow.gif
URL:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/index.html
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>creator</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2007-01-01</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>FCA0E9E3-22DF-4415-B607-F4FA9DB55E2C</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:language>en-US</lom:language><lom:metadataSchema>LOMv1.0</lom:metadataSchema></lom:metaMetadata><lom:rights><lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:cost><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:cost></lom:rights><lom:technical><lom:format/><lom:installationRemarks><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:installationRemarks><lom:location>http://www.k-state.edu/are-cns/architectural_engineering/are_undergrad_curric.html</lom:location><lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:size>0</lom:size></lom:technical></lom:lom>