<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lom:lom xmlns:lom="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM"><lom:educational><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:description><lom:difficulty/><lom:intendedEndUserRole/><lom:interactivityLevel/><lom:interactivityType/><lom:learningResourceType/><lom:semanticDensity/><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:educational><lom:general><lom:aggregationLevel><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>2</lom:value></lom:aggregationLevel><lom:coverage><lom:string language="en-US">united-states</lom:string></lom:coverage><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">Paper presented by J.W. Martin and M.E Haque at the ASEE/IEEE 2001 Frontiers in Education Conference. It examines the status of service-learning in the construction science curriculum at Texas A&amp;M University and proposes a service-learning project for students in the construction science curriculum. From Abstract: " Service Learning is a form of experiential  learning that utilizes the context of a community service  project to practice academic skills.  In recent years Service  learning has been included in many academic disciplines  throughout the United States. Incorporating a hands-on  component into the curriculums of construction science is  challenging for the instructor.  Most often these servicelearning activities are accompanied by lessons in the  classroom creating a pedagogical synergy not found in  singular teaching/learning activities in the traditional  classroom setting.  A difficulty arises when professors want  to develop service-learning projects for courses in  Structures.  This paper examines the current status of  service learning in the Construction Science curriculum and  proposes a service-learning project for Construction Science  students at Texas A&amp;M University. kind of experiences which, while they do not repel the  student, but rather engage his activities are, nevertheless,  more than immediately enjoyable since they promote having  desirable future experiences? [2].  This is the challenge for  engineering and construction educators.  To achieve an effective mix of learning modes, the  construction educator might combine laboratory  experiences, audiovisual components, and group exercises  with lectures.  Approaches such as these are critical for more  effective construction education.  Practical activities can be  as important as the theoretical underpinnings of the  construction management field.  One of the best laboratories  for construction management is the construction project  itself.  There is no substitute for knowledge derived from  guided experience in the field."

Kewywords: Experiential Learning, Service Learning,  Structures Classes, Hands-on, Service-Learning</lom:string></lom:description><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>65E6B9A9-12E4-45CA-AD2C-E73F04D35A6A</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:keyword><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:keyword><lom:structure><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>hierarchical</lom:value></lom:structure><lom:title><lom:string language="en-US">Service Learning: Engineering, Construction Science and the Experiential Curriculum</lom:string></lom:title><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:general><lom:lifeCycle><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:EC90743E-8CCA-40E5-93F9-706619BA94E0
N:M.E. Haque;J.W. Martin and;null;;
FN:J.W. Martin and M.E. Haque
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>author</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2001-06-01</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:version><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:version></lom:lifeCycle><lom:metaMetadata><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:B0BF444F-C039-4252-BEFF-C0B6321C7418
N:Alice Agogino;;;;
FN:Alice Agogino
ADR;TYPE=work,postal,parcel:;;5136 Etcheverry HallUniversity of California at Berkeley;Berkeley;CA;;
TEL;TYPE=work,voice:510-849-0931
TEL;TYPE=work,fax:510-849-1822
PHOTO;VALUE=uri:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/agogino_shadow.gif
URL:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/index.html
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>creator</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2005-03-27</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>65E6B9A9-12E4-45CA-AD2C-E73F04D35A6A</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:language>en-US</lom:language><lom:metadataSchema>LOMv1.0</lom:metadataSchema></lom:metaMetadata><lom:rights><lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>yes</lom:value></lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:cost><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:cost></lom:rights><lom:technical><lom:format/><lom:installationRemarks><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:installationRemarks><lom:location>http://fie.engrng.pitt.edu/fie2001/papers/1028.pdf</lom:location><lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:size>0</lom:size></lom:technical></lom:lom>