<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lom:lom xmlns:lom="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM"><lom:educational><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:description><lom:difficulty/><lom:intendedEndUserRole/><lom:interactivityLevel/><lom:interactivityType/><lom:learningResourceType/><lom:semanticDensity/><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:educational><lom:general><lom:aggregationLevel><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>2</lom:value></lom:aggregationLevel><lom:coverage><lom:string language="en-US">united-states</lom:string></lom:coverage><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">Report is available for free in html format and for a price in print or pdf format. From the Executive Summary: "Through science, mathematics, and engineering, our nation continues to lead the world in the development and utilization of new technologies. Whether related to our health, to the environment, or to our production and use of material goods, science, mathematics, engineering, and technology (SME&amp;T) are integral and essential parts of daily life for virtually everyone in the United States and around the globe. However, the understanding of SME&amp;T by most Americans, which reflects the level of SME&amp;T education most Americans have had, is inadequate for full participation in this increasingly technological world. Our nation is becoming divided into a technologically knowledgeable elite and a disadvantaged majority. Given the large and increasing numbers of students in the higher education system and the fact that all teachers of grades K-12 are products of that system, improving SME&amp;T education, particularly at the undergraduate level, could be a critical means for closing the gap.

Changes are needed in current approaches to teaching SME&amp;T at the undergraduate level as well as in graduate training and continuing education for teachers. To effect these changes is an enormous challenge. However, on campuses across the United States, many individuals are making substantive improvements to SME&amp;T courses, programs, and curricula. The time has now come for the institutionalization and sharing of these improvements. Nothing less than the fundamental reform of American postsecondary SME&amp;T education is at stake.

To guide the institutionalization and sharing of postsecondary SME&amp;T education reform, primarily at the undergraduate level, the authoring committee of this report?the Committee on Undergraduate Science Education (CUSE)?has adopted a primary goal. It is based on five years of research and discussions with members of many sectors of the higher education SME&amp;T community, including two years of intensive research into and consultations about major issues in SME&amp;T undergraduate education."</lom:string></lom:description><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>8567469A-5F96-4DB9-9263-64E18B2B9BB3</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:keyword><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:keyword><lom:structure><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>hierarchical</lom:value></lom:structure><lom:title><lom:string language="en-US">Transforming Undergraduate Education in Science, Mathematics, Engineering and Technology</lom:string></lom:title><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:general><lom:lifeCycle><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:F3F44F40-ADCA-4A8B-8339-183BCB154D75
N:National Academies Press - NAP;Center for Science, Mathematics, and Engineering Education CSME;null;;
FN:Center for Science, Mathematics, and Engineering Education CSME National Academies Press - NAP
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>author</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>1999-01-01</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:version><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:version></lom:lifeCycle><lom:metaMetadata><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:B0BF444F-C039-4252-BEFF-C0B6321C7418
N:Alice Agogino;;;;
FN:Alice Agogino
ADR;TYPE=work,postal,parcel:;;5136 Etcheverry HallUniversity of California at Berkeley;Berkeley;CA;;
TEL;TYPE=work,voice:510-849-0931
TEL;TYPE=work,fax:510-849-1822
PHOTO;VALUE=uri:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/agogino_shadow.gif
URL:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/index.html
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>creator</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2007-01-20</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>8567469A-5F96-4DB9-9263-64E18B2B9BB3</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:language>en-US</lom:language><lom:metadataSchema>LOMv1.0</lom:metadataSchema></lom:metaMetadata><lom:rights><lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:cost><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:cost></lom:rights><lom:technical><lom:format/><lom:installationRemarks><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:installationRemarks><lom:location>http://www.nap.edu/openbook.php?isbn=0309062942</lom:location><lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:size>0</lom:size></lom:technical></lom:lom>