<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lom:lom xmlns:lom="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM"><lom:educational><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:description><lom:difficulty/><lom:intendedEndUserRole/><lom:interactivityLevel/><lom:interactivityType/><lom:learningResourceType/><lom:semanticDensity/><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:educational><lom:general><lom:aggregationLevel><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>2</lom:value></lom:aggregationLevel><lom:coverage><lom:string language="en-US">united-states</lom:string></lom:coverage><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">"Four federal science agencies have made efforts to ensure that grantees  comply with Title IX in the sciences by performing several compliance  activities, such as investigating complaints and providing technical  assistance, but most have not conducted all required monitoring activities.   Agency officials at Energy, NASA, and NSF told us that they refer complaints  to Education and the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, where  they are investigated. However, only Education has monitored its grantees  by conducting compliance reviews￩￩??periodic, agency-initiated assessments  of grantees to determine if they are complying with Title IX.    Women￩￩??s participation in the sciences has increased substantially in the last  three decades, especially in the life sciences, such as biology. The proportion  of women science students has grown, but to a lesser extent at the graduate  level than the undergraduate level. Meanwhile, the proportion of faculty in  the sciences who are women has also increased, but they still lag behind  men faculty in terms of salary and rank. However, studies indicate that  experience, work patterns, and education levels can largely explain these  differences. Studies also suggest that discrimination may still affect women￩￩??s  choices and professional progress." The study "www.gao.gov/cgi-bin/getrpt?GAO-04-639.    To view the full product, including the scope  and methodology, click on the link above.  For more information, contact Cornelia Ashby  We found several examples of agencies and grantees that have instituted  practices designed to foster greater women￩￩??s participation in the sciences.   While some of the practices are aimed at encouraging more women to  pursue the sciences, others provide time off and fewer teaching duties so  faculty can balance work and family life. Finally, a few practices seek to  expand the recruiting pool for jobs in the sciences and make them more  attractive to a greater portion of the U.S. population, including women."  

Keywords: Gender Equity in STEM (science, technology, engineering and mathematics)</lom:string></lom:description><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>9CABA1CB-89AE-441C-9A25-057D99410628</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:keyword><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:keyword><lom:structure><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>hierarchical</lom:value></lom:structure><lom:title><lom:string language="en-US">Women's Participation in the Sciences has Increased, but Agencies Need to Do More to Ensure Compliance with Title IX.</lom:string></lom:title><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:general><lom:lifeCycle><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:E014CC8B-2129-4164-9BEB-B817883AC684
N:United State;Government Accountability Office;null;;
FN:Government Accountability Office United State
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>author</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2004-07-01</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:version><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:version></lom:lifeCycle><lom:metaMetadata><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:3BD3C8E5-C45A-41B5-9D62-CD6961AA4A5A
N:premier-award judge;;;;
FN:premier-award judge
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>creator</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2005-02-17</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>9CABA1CB-89AE-441C-9A25-057D99410628</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:language>en-US</lom:language><lom:metadataSchema>LOMv1.0</lom:metadataSchema></lom:metaMetadata><lom:rights><lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:cost><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:cost></lom:rights><lom:technical><lom:format/><lom:installationRemarks><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:installationRemarks><lom:location>http://www.gao.gov/new.items/d04639.pdf</lom:location><lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:size>0</lom:size></lom:technical></lom:lom>