<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>The Foundations of Program Verification</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>The Foundations of Program Verification Second Edition Jacques Loeckx and Kurt Sieber Fachbereich informatik Universit t des Saariandes, Saarbr amp #252 cken, Germany In collaboration with Ryan D. Stansifer Department of Computer Science    Cornell University, USA This revised edition provides a precise mathematical background to several program verification techniques. It concentrates on those verification methods that have now become classic, such as the inductive assertions method of Floy      d, the axiomatic method of Hoare, and Scott amp #145 s fixpoint induction. The aim of the book is to present these different verification methods in a simple setting and to explain their mathematical background in particular the problems of correctness an      d completeness of the different methods are discussed in some detail and many helpful examples are included. Contents Authors amp #146  Preface LI=0 Part A: Preliminaries OL Mathematical PreliminariesPredicate Log   ic /OL  LI=0 Part B: Semantics of Programming Languages OL start=3 Three Simple Programming LanguagesFixpoints in Complete Partial OrdersDenotational Semantics /OL  LI=0 Part C: Program Verificat   ion Methods OL start=6 Correctness of ProgramsThe Classical Methods of FloydThe Axiomatic Method of HoareVerification Methods Based on Denotational SemanticsLCF A Logic for Computable Functions /O   L  LI=0 Part D: Prospects OL start=11 An Overview of Further Developments /OL  /UL Bibliography Index Review of the First Edition  amp #145  amp #133  one of the better books currently available which introduces progra   m verification. amp #146  G. Bunting, University College Cardiff University Computing</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>