<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Capstone Design Program</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>The Capstone Design Program in the Electrical Engineering department is an innovative two-semester design course sequence consisting of ELEN 493 and ELEN 494. This design course is taught in a way that makes the experience a model of what happens in the real word. One of the great strength of the Electrical Engineering curriculum is the emphasis on fundamentals and how they apply to real-world problems. The ultimate goal of this design course is to bring together seniors in mechanical engineering, manufacturing engineering, electrical engineering business, and industrial design. The Capstone Design Program combines educational elements to produce a unique class environment. These elements include the use of industrially sponsored design and build projects, a structured design approach, the integration of product and manufacturing process design, multi-disciplinary student design teams, and emphasis on engineering and people skills. Student assignments are "deliverables," much the same as would be found in industry. They include: a project schedule, functional specification, concept generation and evaluation, layout design, experimental plan and report, part and process definition, working prototype, production sample, and final documentation. Project deliverables are presented orally to industry representatives, faculty members, and senior students.
The purpose of the Capstone Design Program is threefold: first, to prepare students with a design methodology to be able to successfully do design and manufacturing projects in a cross-functional team setting. Second, to prepare students for the practice of engineering using an interdisciplinary approach working under the direction of a faculty coach. Third, to assist the faculty in enhancing the relevancy of all of their teaching by involving them in working with students on real-life, industrially sponsored projects.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>