<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Cisco Systems-Networking Academy Program</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>The Cisco Networking Academy Program is a comprehensive e-learning program that provides students with the Internet technology skills essential in a global economy. The Networking Academy delivers web-based content, online assessment, student performance tracking, hands-on labs, instructor training and support, and preparation for industry standard certifications.

Launched in October 1997 with 64 educational institutions in seven states, the Networking Academy has spread to more than 150 countries. Since its inception, over 1.6 Million students have enrolled at more than 10,000 Academies located in high schools, technical schools, colleges, universities, and community-based organizations.

Interested educational institutions are given the designation of Networking Academy at the level of training that they will be providing in the program. There are currently three possible tiers of training. Industry experts at Cisco Systems train the Instructor Trainers at the Cisco Academy Training Centers (CATCs), the CATC Instructors train Regional Academy Instructors and the Regional Academy Instructors train the Local Academy Instructors who then educate students. Utilizing this three-tier training model helps to provide instructors the training they need in close proximity to where they are located. Educational institutions may play a role at one or more of these training levels.

Cisco's partners from business, government and community organizations form an ecosystem to deliver the range of services and support needed to grow tomorrow's global workforce. Initially created to prepare students for the Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) and Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP) degrees, the Academy curriculum has expanded with ecosystem-partner sponsored courses. Optional courses include: HP IT Essentials: PC Hardware and Software and HP IT Essentials: Network Operating Systems sponsored by Hewlett-Packard; and Panduit Network Infrastructure Essentials sponsored by Panduit Corporation.

The Internet enables anytime, anywhere learning for all students, regardless of location, socio-economic status, gender, or race. With the United Nations Development Program, the United States Agency for International Development, and the International Telecommunication Union, Cisco has made the Academy program available to students in Least Developed Countries to help them build their country's economies.

The Networking Academy program continually raises the bar on e-learning and educational processes. Through community feedback and electronic assessment, the Academy program adapts curriculum to improve outcomes and student achievement. The Academy infrastructure is designed to deliver a rich, interactive, and personalized curriculum to students around the world. The Internet has the power to change the way people learn, work, and play, and the Cisco Networking Academy Program is in the forefront of this transformation</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>