<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Leveraging an Alternative Source of Computer Scientists: Reentry Programs</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Abstract: Much has been written about the "leaky pipeline" of women in computer science (CS), with the percentage of women decreasing as one moves from lower levels, such as college, to higher levels, culminating in full professorship. While significant attention focused on keeping women from leaving the pipeline, there is also an opportunity to bring women into the pipeline through non-traditional programs, instead of requiring that everyone enter at the undergraduate level. Both Mills College, a small liberal arts institution for women, and UC Berkeley, a large research university, established programs in the 80's to increase the number of women in computer science by tapping non-traditional students. Both programs share the core value of accommodating older students lacking technical backgrounds. The two programs have produced similar results: graduate degrees earned in computer science by students who would not have qualified without these programs, professional employment in the computer science field by women and minorities, and a recognition that this population represents a rich source of talent for our nation.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>