<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>BPC-DP: Information Management and Systems Engineering (Enabling Success in Computing in Detroit)</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Goals: designed to guide and support disadvantage students at critical junctures from a GED through the completion of a post-secondary degree. The IMSE program begins with multiple proven bridge and support activities provided by FOCUS: HOPE including remedial math and reading program, an industry-certified training program in network administration, network installation, and desktop and server administration; professional devlopement workshops; a student load program; a community food bank; and an on-site child-care program. The second phase of the IMSE program combines a BA in Information Systems and Technology offered by WSU with a coordinated support progrm. The cooordinated support plan at WSU includes tutoring and e-mentoring programs, culturally sensitive advising, emerging scholars sections of introductory programming courses, social networking and participation in industry internships and academic research.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>