<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Academic Programs in Resource Management and Environmental Studies (RMES)</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Resource Management and Environmental Studies (RMES) is the interdisciplinary graduate program at IRES that offers Masters of Art, Masters of Science and Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) degrees.  Additionally, RMES offers a Watershed Management Certificate. The academic program is flexible and, to a large extent, tailored to the educational goals of the student.  A thesis proposal/statement of intent is required at the time of formal application to the program in order to facilitate the selection of an appropriate supervisor, supervisory committee and individual academic direction. The RMES program draws from faculty members' expertise from across the University.

The RMES program's research activities address a range of topics related to land management, environmental assessment, policy analysis, coastal zone management, fisheries management, agroforestry, water resource management, hydrology, energy, negotiation issues, risk perception and assessment, issues of governance, science and policy, and community development.

The program's aim is to integrate the socioeconomic (political) and biophysical (ecological) approaches to resource and environmental issues. To achieve these aims, workshops and seminars are common academic formats.

RMES welcomes applications from national and international students of diverse disciplinary backgrounds.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>