<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Chemical  Engineering Curriculum - UC Berkeley</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>* The master's degree program places equal emphasis on advanced course work and on research. A research project and thesis are required of all candidates in order to provide each student with the opportunity for growth and with maturity in independent professional activity.
The specific courses taken in the master's program are selected in consultations between students and the academic adviser. Students are encouraged to broaden their knowledge and to pursue particular specialized interests through their choices of courses.


* The Ph.D. program is designed to enlarge the body of knowledge of the student and, more importantly, to discover and develop talent for original, productive, and creative work in chemical engineering. Breadth of knowledge and professional training are achieved through advanced course work. The course requirement is 30 letter-graded semester units. Twelve units derive from a required core of 4 chemical engineering courses in the areas of mathematics, thermodynamics, reaction engineering, and transport phenomena. An additional 9 unit sequence in an outside specialty is required, and 9 additional units must be taken from departmental graduate electives. In addition to these 30 units, the department recognizes that practicing chemical engineers draw increasingly on information from other disciplines. Students are strongly encouraged to pursue additional courses of specific relevance to their thesis research and to explore other areas of technical, professional, or personal interest.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>