<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Developmentally appropriate LOGO computer programming with young children</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The Iowa Early Childhood Papert Partnership (IECPP), a partnership among two public school systems, a private university school of education, a Head Start agency, a state area educational support agency, and renown technology theorist Seymour Papert, explored ways that LOGO computer programming can be used in developmentally appropriate ways with young children. The National Association for the Education of Young Children (NAEYC), defined developmental-ly appropriate practice as (a) age appropriateness, (b) individual appropriateness, and (c) sociocultural appropriateness. Each of these factors are considered, with particular attention being devoted to the developmental theories of Jean Piaget, Erik Erikson, Howard Gardner, and Lev Vygotsky. It is found that although Piaget is the theorist most commonly cited with reference to young children&#146;s work with computers, LOGO programming by young children is also (perhaps even more strongly) supported by the theories of Erikson, Gardner, and Vygotsky. Implications for practice are discussed in detail, drawing on the experience of those who have introduced the Reggio Emilia approach in their early childhood pro-grams. Implications for curriculum design, pedagogy, family involvement, research, and development are all discussed."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>