<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>NSF ADVANCE  Program at the University of Nevada - ASCENT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Type:  Partnerships for Adaptation, Implementation, and Dissemination;
Year Awarded: 2009. Description: This project will create a discipline-specific, well-designed program focusing on women in atmospheric science/meteorology to create leaders for advancement. The emphasis during the proposed three-day Atmospheric Science Collaborations and Enriching Networks (ASCENT) summer workshop program and follow-up reunion events will be to initiate positive professional relationships, among female faculty of different ranks and postdoctoral researchers. These individuals will work in teams (each senior scientist will be paired with two junior scientists) and foster connections. Furthermore, while networking with like-minded women scientists, participants will have the opportunity to explore specific promising practices toward eliminating the "leaky pipeline," defined by the attrition of women at different stages in their academic careers. By fostering relationships among women faculty and researchers, ASCENT will demonstrate a commitment to developing research bases and improve the quality of collaborative atmospheric research conducted at multiple universities and colleges.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>