<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Freshman Engineering Honors Program</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Syllabi and course materials for the freshman Engineering Honors three-course sequence. Includes lecture presentations, procedures, and student resources.
As part of the Gateway Engineering Education Coalition, Ohio  State has developed two first year engineering programs.  The first one, the Freshman Engineering Honors program (or FEH) is optional for Honors students (~25% of the ~1100 entering engineering freshmen) and the second one is the required program for all freshmen and is called the Introduction to Engineering Program (or IEP).

 

The FEH program is an elective set of coordinated courses from Engineering, Physics, and Mathematics.  There are three Engineering courses (one per quarter), two or optionally three Physics courses, and either of two sets of three calculus courses. In the Spring Quarter there are some optional courses in chemistry and engineering mechanics for the third physics course. Contained at this site is the documentation for the engineering portion of the FEH program.  The documentation for engineering sequence of courses contains syllabi, text references, PowerPoint slides for lectures, PowerPoint slides for hands-on lab lectures, pictures and descriptions of lab set-ups, and descriptions of the design projects.  Longitudinal tracking has shown that students who participate in this program are retained at a rate of 80-90 percent compared to a matched control group where the retention rate was 70 percent.   

 

Freshman year are registered for their sophomore year.  Tracking also shows that 82% of the students who took the program in 1999 are still registered in Engineering for Autumn 2001.  Past retention figures showed that only 50% of the freshman actually enroll for their junior year in Engineering.
Keywords: Freshman design, case studies, freshman labs</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>