<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Interprofessional Projects Program - IPRO</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"An IPRO project course is a team-based learning environment in which students from various concentrations and disciplines work together to solve a real-world problem. Through the experience of working on this problem, students have the opportunity to apply and develop their teamwork, project management, communication, and ethical behavior skills. There is a wide range of topics proposed by sponsors, faculty and students that includes all of IIT?s disciplines and professional programs. The IPRO projects offered each semester are constantly changing to reflect emerging trends in technology and the needs of society.

Each IPRO course is organized as a team of 5-15 students from sophomore to graduate level. All projects are designed with goals that can be completed in one semester. However, many projects continue over multiple semesters and years, with continuing areas of investigation. No two semesters are ever alike. An Entrepreneurial IPRO (EnPRO) has the added dimension of business planning and new venture analysis.

The interprofessional course is an IIT general education requirement. All undergraduates must complete at least two 3 credit IPRO courses. Graduate students are encouraged to enroll in an IPRO project course as well, and may receive elective credit toward their degree."
Keywords: Interdisciplinary design, capstone design, teamwork</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>