<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Concurrent Programming Using Java</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>The material shown on this website is covered in much more detail in the book, Concurrent Programming: The Java Programming Language, published by Oxford University Press in March 1998. 
This site provides an introduction to the Java programming language in concurrent or multithreaded applications. The tutorial was designed for process synchronization material and related concurrent programming in operating systems courses as opposed to software engineering. Topics include: genetic algorithms, threads, semaphores, monitors,  critical sections, mutual exclusion, message passing, the rendezvous, remote procedure calls, distributed or network programming, and parallel processing. Solutions to the classical problems talked about in operating systems courses (the dining philosophers, the bounded buffer producers and consumers, and the database readers and writers) are shown in Java. Also shown is how to animate algorithms using the command set of the Xtango animation interpreter, animator. Some of the animation examples can be viewed as applets.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>