<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Nuclear Engineering Curriculum - Oregon State</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The Oregon State University graduate program in nuclear engineering was established in 1959 as a degree program through the Mechanical Engineering department. The newly formed program included a small AGN-201 training reactor, the first nuclear reactor in the state of Oregon. The Nuclear Engineering Department was established as a separate entity in 1972. That same year, the undergraduate nuclear engineering program received accreditation for six years by the Engineering Council for Professional Development. In 1978, the nuclear engineering and nuclear engineering technology programs were both accredited for an additional six years. In the same year, the nuclear engineering technology program was suspended for lack of enrollment. The last nuclear engineering technology student graduated in 1981, and the program has since been discontinued. The most recent Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology (A.B.E.T.) review was performed in 2002 with accreditation granted through 2008. The Nuclear Engineering graduate program has a long record of success and continues to be a vital part of the College of Engineering."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>