<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>NSF ADVANCE  Program at Wayne State University - ESCALATE</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Type:  Partnerships for Adaptation, Implementation, and Dissemination;
Year Awarded: 2006.

Description: The ESCALATE program, in collaboration with the NSF-sponsored ADVANCE program at the University of Michigan, advances on two fronts, career development and climate change, by developing and implementing nine strategies to improve the advancement of women in academic science and engineering at Wayne State University. This project focuses on broad-based institutional change in sciences and engineering, departmental change in two engineering programs and career development activities for women faculty in sciences and engineering. Infusing Institutional Climate Change: A Resource Team is formed from applicants interested in learning more about women's circumstances and strategies for institutional change, as well as willing to work for change in the campus community. The UM Theater Group will present interactive workshops to campus leaders that teach about equity in hiring and tenure processes, and about mentoring. WSU initiates and participates in a Joint Urban Presence intended to develop strategies for sharing skills known to be effective in working with urban students. Departmental Transformation: Two engineering departments will engage in self-study and develop strategies for increasing women's numbers and advancement.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>