<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>CCSU's Mechanical Engineering Program Approved by DHE; New Program a "Natural Fit" for Central</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>CCSU's Mechanical Engineering Program Approved by DHE; New Program a "Natural Fit" for Central
Summary: News article about Central Connecticut State University's new bachelor of science program in mechanical engineering that builds on the Engineer 2020 reports. Dr. Zdzislaw Kremens, Dean of CCSU's School of Technology is cited saying "that the school will seek to have the program accredited at its first opportunity: when the first group of students graduate. We designed the program with ABET [Accreditation Board for Engineering &amp; Technology] accreditation standards in mind. Since we already offer three ABET-accredited programs [Mechanical Engineering Technology, Manufacturing Engineering Technology, and Civil Engineering Technology], I am confident that the ME program will earn accreditation, too." Kremens said that School of Technology faculty designed the curriculum to be "forward looking," drawing from a comprehensive report produced by the National Academy of Engineers: The Engineer of 2020. "That report, especially with its emphasis on the urgent need to teach en!
 gineering that connects applied sciences, engineering design, and solutions to real-world problems, was a crucial component in our development of our program," Kremens said.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>