<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Undergraduate Mechancial Engineering Curriculum - Cornell</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The Sibley School offers an exciting and dynamic curriculum  taught by world    class    faculty   in   fields   such   as biomechanics,  automotive  engineering,  fluid mechanics,   and   control   systems.   Cornell offers  a  variety  of   research  opportunities, hands-on   projects   and   Co-op / internship programs.

Undergraduates earn a B.S. in Mechanical Engineering.  An overview of the Major Program in Mechanical Engineering is shown here as part of the Common Curriculum requirements for an engineering degree at Cornell. The Major program is inside the dashed box; the overview shows the requirements for a student who has no advanced placement credit. An example is provided to show how this basic program can be modified to meet Pre-Med requirements. 

The Major Program is designed to provide a broad background in the fundamentals of Mechanical Engineering as well as to offer an introduction to the many professional and technical areas with which mechanical engineers are concerned. The program covers both major streams of the major of mechanical engineering."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>