<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Materials Science and Engineering Curriculum - Cornell</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The graduate Field of Materials Science and Engineering provides an opportunity for students from widely different backgrounds to undertake research and study in metals, ceramics, polymers, electronic materials, and geological materials. The approximately ninety graduate students now enrolled have undergraduate degrees in physics or applied physics, and in mechanical, metallurgical, chemical, and electrical engineering, as well as materials science. Much of the research is conducted in connection with the interdisciplinary Materials Science Center, one of the largest such university centers supported by the federal government. The center makes available to faculty members and students a variety of modern and often very expensive equipment, and it provides financial assistance for graduate students through research assistantships. The materials science and engineering faculty also cooperates closely with the National Nanofabrication Facility and with the Cornell High Energy Synchrotron Source.

The department's collaboration with industries engaged in materials research makes a valuable contribution to graduate education. The Materials Science and Engineering Industrial Affiliates Program promotes contact and the exchange of information between member companies and the department. The Polymer Outreach Program, which is part of the Materials Science Center, fosters industrial participation in basic research in polymer science and engineering. The Industry-Cornell Electronic Packaging Alliance is a joint research effort sponsored by several companies with interests in the emerging technologies of this important area."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>