<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Bioengineering Curriculum - UC San Diego</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>" 	
Overview
Bioengineering, one of the youngest engineering disciplines, employs the principles and tools of traditional engineering specialties that are applied to solve biomedical problems. Bioengineering is broad in its spectrum, with its foundation in all of the engineering sciences, as well as physiology and other biomedical sciences. Bioengineering at UCSD was established in 1966 as a joint program between the School of Medicine and the Department of AMES. In recognition of the unique features and requirements of bioengineering and the excellence of the Bioengineering faculty and programs, the University of California established a new Department of Bioengineering in August 1994. In 2000, US News and World Report ranked Bioengineering at UCSD number 3 among all biomedical engineering programs in the nation. In 1995, the National Research Council of the National Academy of Science, National Academy of Engineering and the Institute of Medicine published a comprehensive report in which they ranked the UCSD Bioengineering graduate program number 1 in the nation for effectiveness in teaching and number 2 for scholarly quality. At UCSD, the cooperative arrangement between the Schools of Engineering and Medicine is the foundation of this success by providing an ideal research and training environment that leads to effective collaborations between engineers and medical scientists."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>