<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Materials Engineering Curriculum - UC Santa Barbara</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The Materials Department offers programs leading to the Ph.D. degree with specializations in the following major areas: Electronic Materials (compound semiconductors, quantum structures, advanced lasers, solid state lighting, microelectromechanical systems); Inorganic Materials (ferroelectrics, optical materials, zeolite molecular sieves and catalysts); Macromolecular and Biomolecular Materials (self-assembling polymers, complex fluids, biopolymers, biomembranes, conducting and photonic polymers), and Structural Materials (advanced alloys, ceramics, composites, coatings, structural polymers, multifunctional materials).

The curriculum in each area has the flexibility needed to provide multidisciplinary educational opportunities in the field of advanced materials, encompassing topics such as optoelectronic devices, composites, and micromechanics. Materials synthesis, processing and characterization feature prominently with courses in the processing of ceramics, alloys, composites, semiconductor materials, and polymers, as well as advanced topics in electron microscopy. Programs of study and research are individually tailored to accommodate research needs and student interest. Multidisciplinary education is strongly encouraged by means of joint faculty supervision of research and by the selection of courses. Students are also encouraged to cross over traditional boundaries into other campus departments (for example, Electrical and Computer Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, Chemical Engineering, Biology, Chemistry and Physics) through collaboration and taking courses in those departments, as appropriate. There is no foreign language requirement."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>