<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>BPC-DP: BTU - "Build it, Trust it, Use It" Project</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Goals:
The Build it, Trust it, Use it project (BTU) is funded through the National Science Foundation&#146;s Broadening Participation in Computing (BPC) and Information Technology for Students and Teachers (ITEST) programs and brings together Northern Kentucky University faculty from the departments of social work and computer science, in partnership with social service agencies (Centro De Amistad), the Latino and Multicultural Center for Regional Development, and area businesses to develop and provide an innovative program designed to expose participating Hispanic families to computing technologies via a hands-on curriculum model.

Faculty and students at Northern Kentucky University team up to serve as leaders of ten-week workshops. Offered after hours and on weekends at a local Hispanic community center, these bilingual workshops involve middle school students and their parents in informal but structured introductions to computer hardware and software. The program engages Hispanic professionals from local corporations to serve as mentors in the program. Program teams conduct and analyze surveys of participant attitudes toward IT before and after each workshop.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>