<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Chemical  Engineering Curriculum - University of Minnesota</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The Department of Chemical Engineering and Materials Science at the University of Minnesota has been renowned for its pioneering scholarly work and for its influence in graduate education for the past half-century. Our department has produced numerous legendary engineering scholars and current leaders in both academia and industry.

With its pacesetting research and education program in chemical engineering encompassing reaction engineering, multiphase flow, statistical mechanics, polymer science and bioengineering, our department was the first to foster a far-reaching marriage of the Chemical Engineering and Materials Science programs into an integrated department. For the past few decades, the chemical engineering program has been consistently ranked as the top graduate program in the country by the National Research Council and other ranking surveys.

Our education and training are known not only for rigorously delving into specific and in-depth subjects, but also for their breadth and global perspectives. The widely ranging collection of high-impact research projects in these world-renowned laboratories provides students with a unique experience, preparing them for careers that are both exciting and rewarding."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>