<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Environmental Engineering Curriculum - Georgia Tech</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Environmental Engineering at Georgia Tech provides unique educational and research opportunities in the fields of water quality and treatment, wastewater reclamation and reuse, hazardous and solid waste engineering, ground water modeling and treatment, air pollution control and modeling, environmental sciences and industrial ecology. Because of the multidisciplinary credentials of its faculty and the excellence of its research facilities, the program attracts high caliber students from a variety of engineering and science backgrounds. Environmental Engineering (EnvE) is also a key component in the campus initiative on Environmental Science &amp; Technology (ES&amp;T) with faculty in the School of Chemical Engineering (ChE), School of Earth &amp; Atmospheric Sciences (EAS), and programs in Environmental Biology and Environmental Chemistry. 

Course offerings in EnvE emphasize basic engineering and scientific principles, system design and applications of environmental engineering operations and processes. Core courses for the MS program are also offered through a distance-learning degree program. Programs at the MS and Ph.D. levels are specifically designed for individual students and matched with faculty expertise and professional goals of students. "</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>