<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Civil Engineering Curriculum - University of California at Berkeley</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Listed below are the six graduate programs in Civil and Environmental Engineerng at UC Berkeley:

        * Engineering &amp; Project Management (formerly Construction Engineering &amp; Management)
        * Environmental Engineering
        * GeoEngineering
        * Structural Engineering, Mechanics and Materials
        * Transportation Engineering
        * Civil Systems: This interdisciplinary program cuts across all of these emphasis areas. 

    Graduate students select courses in their programs of study in consultation with an assigned graduate advisor in their major field. All students are required to maintain a full-time load of 12 units. The Department does not allow part-time graduate study.

    The Master of Science program consists of a minimum of 24 units of course work with a comprehensive examination (some groups within the Department may have other requirement options in lieu of the comprehensive exam). It is normally completed in two semesters. A thesis plan for the Master of Science degree is also possible.

    The Master of Engineering program consists of 40-44 units of course work including an independent study and report. The normal time to attain a M.Eng. degree is four semesters.  The Master degree programs require a minimum GPA of 3.0 out of 4 for graduation.

    Students are admitted to the doctoral program following attainment of a Master of Science degree in civil and environmental engineering or in another related field. Doctoral studies consist of selected courses, examinations, and independent research culminating in a thesis.  Final programs are individually formulated through consultation with a faculty guidance committee. Each doctoral student must satisfy, through course work, a major within the Department. In addition, two minor areas of course work are required that are appropriate for the student's area of research. "</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>