<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Mechancial Engineering Curriculum - Purdue</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>""Built on a long tradition of excellence, the School of Mechanical Engineering has become synonymous with accomplishment and leadership in engineering education and engineering research. Forty-nine faculty are dedicated to educating over 1100 undergraduate and graduate students, and to maintaining and developing world-class research programs. These research programs complement our educational mission, address the evolving needs of industry and society, and contribute to economic and social development.

Today, more than ever before, the knowledge and skills of talented persons with advanced degrees in mechanical engineering are vitally needed to serve our society. The diversity of the field has made the work of mechanical engineers critical to problem solving in virtually every field of technology.

Purdue University's School of Mechanical Engineering is shaping its academic programs around these challenges and we are proud to offer our graduate students the education needed for success in the twenty-first century.

The graduate program in Purdue University's School of Mechanical Engineering is one of the oldest and most distinguished in the United States. Over the years, the School has acquired an international reputation for excellence in its wide-ranging curriculum and diverse research activities. "</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>