<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Biomedical Engineering Curriculum - Case Western</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>" Medicine is undergoing a transformation based on the rapid advances in science and technology that are combining to produce more accurate diagnoses, more effective treatments with fewer side effects, and improved ability to prevent disease. The goal of the MD/MS in Engineering is to prepare medical graduates to be leaders in the development and clinical deployment of this technology and to partner with others in technology based translational research teams.

Recent developments in the School of Medicine have opened opportunities to achieve this goal. Research is now a requirement of the MD degree. The new Cleveland Clinic Lerner College of Medicine (CCLCM), a separate college within the School of Medicine, prepares physicians for research careers through a five-year program requiring a master's level research thesis. In addition, students in the medical school's University Program (UP) must complete a research project as a graduation requirement.

The MD/MS in Engineering provides an opportunity for students in either the University or CCLCM programs to obtain expertise and to perform research in engineering with an emphasis in translational biomedical research. The MD/MS in Engineering provides an integrated experience in which the clinical MD training complements the engineering training, and the thesis research integrates the two.

At this time, a track in Biomedical Engineering (BME) is available. It is anticipated that other tracks may be offered in the future. A Track Executive Committee (TEC, see below) with a designated Track Leader administers each track. The remainder of this document applies to the BME Track. "</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>