<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Women in Computing Programs: Does the Incredible Shrinking Pipeline Apply to All Computing Programs</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Abstract: Despite the fact that demand for employees with skills in computing still exceeds supply, there has been a steady decline in the number of women entering and graduating from computer science programs. Many attempts have been made to remedy the situation. A recurrent theme for both engineering and computer science programs is that programs can be made more attractive to women if they place a greater emphasis on applications of the technology. To date, most of the research on the under-representation of women has been conducted on computer science programs, and ignores the fact that many students enter the IT workplace with degrees in Information Systems (IS) or Information Technology (IT). Moreover, programs in IS and IT place a greater emphasis on applications. Given the reported importance of applications for the recruitment and retention of women, one might expect to see a higher participation of women in these programs. Using data obtained from baccalaureate or above institutions within the University System of Georgia, this paper shows that this indeed seems to be the case.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>