<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>BPC-DP: African-American Researchers in Computing Sciences (AARCS)</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Auburn University is leading African-American Researchers in Computing Sciences (AARCS), a program that aims to broaden the participation of African-Americans at the levels of tenure track faculty and research scientist in the computing sciences.

African-Americans represent 5.2% of all university faculties in the United States of America. In Computer Science, African-Americans represent 1.1% of the faculty, 0.88% of tenure track faculty. The African-American Researchers in Computing Sciences (AARCS) program will address this significant representation gap in the computing sciences. This program is designed to broaden African-American participation at the tenure track faculty and research scientist levels of the education pipeline in the form of a demonstration project. The basis for this demonstration project is founded on empirical research conducted by social scientists that reinforce the program&#146;s goals.

Although African-Americans are the target group for this program, the AARCS program will serve as a model that can be used to target other underrepresented groups. The AARCS program will serve as an empirically evaluated model that can be incorporated into larger Alliance projects.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>