<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Disabilities, opportunities, internetworking, and technology: Seattle's DO-IT program</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Since the inception of the Disabilities, Opportunities, Internetworking, and Technology (DO-IT) Scholars program in 1992, more than 200 students with a variety of disabilities have successfully transitioned from secondary schools to postsecondary education and employment settings. DO-IT Scholars are high school students who want to pursue postsecondary studies and careers but face significant challenges due to their disabilities. While participating in the program they develop self-determination skills, along with social, academic, and career skills that are necessary preparation for postsecondary studies and careers. The program has three key components: a) a two-week residential Summer Study, b) year-round computer and Internet activities, and c) career preparation. A key strategy employed in all of these components is significant use of technology designed primarily to support students with disabilities."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>