<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Nuclear Engineering Curriculum - Texas A&amp;M</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"One of the largest and best nuclear engineering programs in the United States, we offer graduate and undergraduate degrees in nuclear engineering and radiological health engineering (or health physics), and have a solid reputation as one of the best-equipped nuclear engineering departments in the country.

Our undergraduate and graduate programs are recognized as perhaps the most challenging majors on campus, but they're also some of the most rewarding. Our students are the most highly recruited graduates at Texas A&amp;M.

A large faculty with diverse research expertise and facilities that are second to none give us the tools we need to equip you with the skills necessary for a career in nuclear science and technology.

Topic areas: Nuclear energy, nuclear forces and related areas, including ion/solid interactions, nuclear reactor design and operation, reactor safety, fusion technology, plasma science and pulsed power, health physics, two-phase flow and heat transfer, computational fluid dynamics, intelligent computer-aided reactor systems design, knowledge-based systems for reactor diagnostics and operation, and "aerosols and clusters" in health physics and materials technology."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>