<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Environmental Engineering Curriculum - CMU</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Graduate programs in the Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering prepare students for leadership roles in engineering practice, development and research. Although students typically focus their studies in one the areas of specialization within the department, interdisciplinary work is strongly encouraged. Joint programs with the Carnegie Mellon Schools of Architecture and Business exist. The environmental engineering, science, and management (air quality, environmental management, green design, water quality, and geo-informatics) program is one of the areas of specialization. The interactions of fundamental physical, chemical and biological processes have given rise to the unique diversity, complexity, and tenacity of Planet Earth and its inhabitants.  Acute or protracted environmental change, whether global or local, natural or anthropogenic, present a grand challenge to scientists and engineers and necessitate a coordinated, multi-disciplinary effort to identify and understand these changes and help define our role in the stewardship of Planet Earth.

The Environmental Engineering Science and Management (EESM) program in CEE at Carnegie Mellon is a comprehensive course of graduate study that addresses the macro-, micro- and nano-scale issues related to protection and restoration of air, soil and water quality, green product and process design, and environmental sustainability.
Graduate courses and research opportunities exist in climate change; sustainable engineering; alternative energy; urban watersheds; fundamental physical, chemical and biological processes in environmental systems and treatment processes; energy management; sustainable infrastructure; computational modeling on molecular and global scales; air quality; environmental microbiology and biotechnology; nanoscience and technology.  Multidisciplinary education and research is emphasized, including opportunities for integrated field and laboratory studies."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>