<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Boeing Welliver Faculty Fellowship Program</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>The Boeing Welliver Faculty Fellowship Program is two fold:

    * To provide faculty with a better understanding of the practical industry application of engineering, information technology and business skills, to influence the content of undergraduate education in ways that will better prepare tomorrow's graduates for careers in a global environment. Program participants are asked to apply this increased knowledge and understanding within their courses and disciplines and too influence broader curriculum changes in a holistic way that addresses the needs of the practitioner.
    * To have faculty observe the Boeing environments, processes, and procedures with "fresh perspectives." Faculty will bring their expertise to bear by documenting their observations at Boeing and by making suggestions for improvement. Faculty in all engineering, manufacturing, information technology and business (i.e. Global Management, Finance, Supply Chain Management, Organization Development/Effectiveness, Leadership; Information Systems Management) disciplines are encouraged to apply. [Note: Only faculty members at the Associate Professor level or above are the target population for this program. Those at the Assistant Professor level or below are generally asked to apply at a later date when tenure has been granted.]</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>