<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Computer Engineering Curriculum -Georgia Tech</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The graduate programs in ECE are among the very best in the world and are consistently rated very highly in the annual U.S. News &amp; World Report graduate program rankings. In the 2007 edition, both the computer engineering and electrical engineering programs placed seventh in their respective categories.

ECE graduate degree options at Georgia Tech include the M.S./M.S.E.C.E. non-thesis option, the M.S./M.S.E.C.E. thesis option, and the Ph.D.  These degrees may be pursued at the main Georgia Tech campus, as well as at Georgia Tech Savannah; at Georgia Tech Lorraine, the Institute???s European campus; and at the Georgia Tech Shanghai campus in China. For more specific information, visit the degrees offered section of the ECE web site.

Graduate students may choose from a variety of technical areas in which to pursue their master???s and doctoral studies. ECE is home to 10 technical interest groups and is a lead or primary player in many different interdisciplinary research centers that attract a broad array of corporate, governmental, and research foundation support. Students can also gain valuable work experience not only in ECE through graduate assistantships, but also through the Cooperative Education Program and the Georgia Tech Research Institute."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>