<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Software Engineering Curriculum - CMU</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Carnegie Mellon has established the Institute for Software Research International (ISRI) in the School of Computer Science (SCS) as a center of excellence for long-term interdisciplinary fundamental research, apprenticeship-based education and training, and international collaborations to address the challenge of designing, developing, integrating, validating, and maintaining practical, large-scale, high-quality software-intensive systems. The creation of the ISRI is a natural extension of Carnegie Mellon's long-standing commitment to research in software systems.

ISRI research activities include experimental prototyping, empirical modeling, codification of experience, formal analysis, creating design/development strategies for modern software, and developing public policy positions.  The educational activities are tightly integrated with the research and demonstration projects.

ISRI's Software Engineering PhD program infuses the research agenda with deep appreciation of the practical issues of developing product-quality software-intensive systems."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>