<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>NSF ADVANCE Program at the University of Alabama at Birmingham</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>The ADVANCE program works to increase the representation and advancement of women in academic science and engineering careers, thereby developing a more diverse science and engineering workforce. The goal of UAB ADVANCE is to improve visibility and recruitment of women in the schools of Natural Science and Mathematics, Social and Behavioral Sciences, and Engineering.

The goals of UAB ADVANCE are to:

   1. increase visibility and awareness of issues related to women faculty
   2. enhance the recruitment of women faculty
   3. enhance the retention of women faculty. 

All UAB ADVANCE program activities are related to these goals.
OAWSE: NSF LogoThe National Science Foundation (NSF) seeks to support new approaches to improving the climate for women in U.S. academic institutions and to facilitate women&#146;s advancement to the highest ranks of academic leadership. UAB is one of 19 academic institutions implementing the ADVANCE program though the NSF Institution Transformational Award. The intent is that activities undertaken by the awardees become models to be replicated in institutions throughout the nation.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>