<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Senior Design Program - Mechanical Engineering - UT Austin</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>The ME Senior Design Projects Program coordinates the completion of the two-semester capstone design sequence required of all UT-Austin Mechanical Engineering seniors. Students apply engineering design methodology, using both analysis and synthesis, to solve open-ended problems submitted by industrial sponsors. The range of design problems considered spans other engineering fields as well as non-engineering disciplines. Regular sponsors in recent years include  Ford Motor Company,  Schlumberger,  Applied Materials,  Lockheed Martin,  Dell, Inc.,  Fluor Daniel,  National Instruments, and  Texas Instruments.

Students register for ME266K (lecture), and ME266P (lab). In the lab sections, which comprise approximately five teams each, teaching assistants monitor the students' progress by means of informal meetings, oral presentations, and notebook checks. The lectures do not consider the specifics of each semester's projects - instead, general design issues and professional responsibility are addressed. Topics include engineering ethics, intellectual property, safety, and product and personal liability. Student participation is an integral component of the lecture periods. The questions asked and issues raised by the class guide the course of discussion. 
Keywords: Capstone design</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>