<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Reactor Analysis Program (ReaCat)</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Used to evaluate and analyze multi-phase and catalytic reactors to suggest to the plant and process engineers the best reactor type and operating conditions.  ReaCat is a reactor analysis program that is being developed by Dr.J.R. Hopper and Dr.J.M. Saleh at Lamar University. It is a component of the advanced on-line process optimization analysis system for pollution prevention (Pike et. al.1998) and can also be used as a stand alone program. The reactor analysis and design tool, ReaCat, is to be used to evaluate and analyze multi-phase and catalytic reactors to suggest to  the plant and process engineers the best reactor type and operating conditions. 

ReaCat incorporates models to design the following reactor types: plug flow, CSTR, batch, catalytic fixed-bed, catalytic fluidized-bed, gas-liquid stirred tank, packed bed, trickle bed, three-phase fixed bubble bed, bubble slurry column, CSTR slurry, three-phase fluidized-bed. ReaCat uses interactive windows to enter information to describe multiple reaction systems upto 30 reactions and 36 components. Error checking is also incorporated to ensure consistency of  input data. The program can handle various energy models such as isothermal, adiabatic or non-adiabatic. The results are presented in graphs or tables which include temperature, pressure, concentration, conversion as a function of reactor length, volume or space time.  
Keywords: Mineral Engineering, Chemical Engineering</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>