<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>BS Degree Program in Construction Management at North Dakota State University</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Construction management is a combination of:

    * engineering technology
    * construction techniques
    * management 

The program is designed to prepare students for the art of achieving maximum profit by efficient use of people, machines, materials, and money to complete a construction project on time and to the satisfaction of the owner. A melding of engineering, construction, management, and business gives the student a background and understanding of managementâ??s point of view in the construction industry. The Construction Management program is accredited by the American Council for Construction Education.

Junior and senior Construction Management majors must maintain a minimum 2.50 institutional grade point average to be eligible for enrollment in 300 and 400 level courses offered by the College of Business Administration. A Minor in Business Administration is a graduation requirement."

Departmental goals: 
"# To provide a positive environment that promotes the scholarship of teaching, the scholarship of research, and the scholarship of service.
# To provide a positive environment that promotes collaboration, team work, discovery, and professional development for both faculty and students.
# To establish and maintain the institutional support and financial resources to recruit, develop, and retain faculty and students who are committed to fulfilling the educational objectives and outcomes of the Construction Management Program and the Construction Engineering Program.
# To provide the resources required to support the Construction Management Program and the Construction Engineering Program.
# To maintain accreditation for both the Construction Management Program (ACCE) and the Construction Engineering Program (ABET)."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>