<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Advancing minority institutions' cyberinfrastructure through the AN-MSI program</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"In January of 2003, the National Science Foundation Blue-Ribbon Advisory Panel on Cyberinfrastructure released its report on the cyberinfrastructure improvements necessary to keep our nation at the forefront of scientific and technological development.1 In this report, Atkins et al. recommended that the NSF set aside $1 billion in funding per year to establish a program that would &#147;create, deploy, and apply cyberinfrastructure in ways that radically empower all scientific and engineering research and allied education&#148; (ES p.1). However, the panel&#146;s recommendations went beyond increasing the speed and sophistication of high performance computing tools. Like numerous others at NSF, Atkins et al. also recognized the importance of making sure that all universities and colleges&#151;regardless of size, budget, and student demographics&#151;have an opportunity to participate in and benefit from cyberinfrastruture developments so that no class of institutions, no group of faculty researchers, and no population of students is left behind."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>