<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>NSF ADVANCE  Program at the University of Miami - SEEDS</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Type:  Partnerships for Adaptation, Implementation, and Dissemination;
Year Awarded: 2008.

Description: The University of Miami's SEEDS (Scientists and Engineers Expanding Diversity and Success) initiative has two main objectives: 1) to implement innovative and proven programs for faculty recruitment and retention and 2) to use these to leverage a larger institutional commitment that will assure continuity and permanence of institutional change. UM is establishing a University-level SEEDS office as a focus for diversity programs across all three UM campuses, establishing a Best Practices Committee to assess equity in policies, funding an Interactive Theatre initiative to help educate academic populations in diversity issues, and sponsoring a comprehensive climate survey to identify gender and ethnicity issues at UM. The SEEDS office will orchestrate initiatives, develop a comprehensive website and work with the Best Practices Committee to educate departments, department chairs and search committees on diversity issues, efforts funded by UM. NSF funding will support seven programs, including five based on proven programs: SEEDS Networking, Senior Scholar Lectureships, Career Workshops, "You Choose" Leadership Opportunities and Mentoring Across Differences, and two novel programs: "Early Career Research Conferences" and "Working From Within For Departmental Transformation".</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>