<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Environmental Science  Engineering Curriculum - Cal Tech</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The Environmental Science and Engineering (ESE) Program offers a coherent program of education and research spanning the large scales of global climate studies to the local scales of engineering solutions to environmental problems such as toxic waste remediation. Reflecting the interdisciplinary nature of environmental science and engineering, the ESE Program unites scientists from Caltech's Division of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Division of Engineering and Applied Sciences, and Division of Geological and Planetary Sciences in studies of the functioning and coupling of the atmosphere, hydrosphere, biosphere, and lithosphere.

Research in the ESE Program addresses, for example, air and water quality, past and potential future climate changes, and the dynamics of biogeochemical cycles and ecosystems (see the faculty pages). The methods employed in research projects include laboratory studies of fundamental chemical and biological processes; field studies of soil microbiology and of atmospheric chemistry; and computational modeling of chemical and physical processes on molecular to global scales. In addition to the facilities of individual research groups, staff and students in the ESE Program have access to a number of shared facilities, including the Environmental Analysis Center, the Center for Advanced Computing Research, and facilities at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>