<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>BPC-A: AccessComputing</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>BPC Alliance Partners: AccessComputing is led by the Department of Computer Science and Engineering and DO-IT at the University of Washington. Project partners include the NSF-funded Regional Alliances for Persons with Disabilities, Gallaudet University, Microsoft, and SIGACCESS of Association for Computing Machinery (ACM).

Goals: The goal of the Alliance for Access to Computing Careers (AccessComputing) is to increase the participation of people with disabilities in computing careers.  Alliance collaborators apply proven practices to:
- increase the number of students with disabilities successfully pursuing undergraduate and graduate degrees and careers in computing fields.
- increase the capacity of postsecondary computing departments to fully include students with disabilities in computing courses and programs.
- create a nationwide resource to help students with disabilities pursue computing fields and assist computing educators and employers, professional organizations, and other stakeholders develop more inclusive programs and share effective practices.  NOTE: This project is an extension of an award from 2005.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>