<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Engineering and Business for Sustainability Certificate Program</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>The Engineering and Business for Sustainability (EBS) Certificate Program is a new initiative to train UC Berkeley graduate students to understand the complexity and urgency of their role in engineering, business, and environmental management, and to work across boundaries to achieve sustainable solutions to pressing societal problems. EBS courses will allow graduate students to tap into the university's vast multidisciplinary educational resources in the College of Engineering, Haas School of Business, Energy and Resources Group, Goldman School of Public Policy, College of Natural Resources, School of Public Health, and potentially other schools. The goal of the EBS Certificate Program is to produce a cadre of influential problem solvers who can have a lasting beneficial impact on the global environment. The EBS Certificate Program is the first certificate program approved at the highest campus level under formal campus guidelines established in 2006. It has also been approved by the College of Engineering.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>