<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Energy Resource Engineering Curriculum at Stanford University</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Formerly the Department of Petroleum Engineering, the graduate program on Energy Resource Engineering focuses on the fundamentals of flow through porous media, geostatistics to represent geological heterogeneity, improved techniques for reservoir simulation, horizontal wells, heavy oil recovery, well test analysis, geothermal energy and reservoir optimization. Our ultimate research goals are to improve recovery from oil, gas and geothermal fields, and to solve problems in containment transport and water resources.
The department offers Master of Science (M.S.), Engineer (Eng.) and Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) degrees in petroleum engineering.

Master of Science
 A total of 45 units is required for the M.S. program. There is a research and a non-research option. All students supported by the department, and students who plan to do a Ph.D. must complete the research option. Most students complete the M.S. degree in six quarters or fewer.

Engineer Degree
 This degree permits more extensive course work than the master's degree, with an emphasis on professional practice. The degree requires 90 units of course work and research beyond a bachelor's degree and is normally completed in two to three years.

Doctor of Philosophy
 Students without an M.S. (or equivalent) in petroleum engineering are required to complete an M.S. at Stanford before entering the Ph.D. program. The degree requires 72 units of course work and research beyond a master's degree and usually takes three to four years. The Ph.D. is awarded primarily on the basis of completion of significant, original research."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>