<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Geometric Aspects of Protein Structure and Function</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Questions of chemical reactivity can often be cast as questions of molecular geometry. In particular, space-filling models are often invoked to rationalize the chemical behavior of proteins. Examples include linking the driving force for protein folding to solvent accessible surface area and the affinity for ligand protein binding to the mechanical fit of a ligand within a protein receptor site. Current numerical techniques do not provide a unified approach to these key geometric aspects of protein structure and function. Questions inadequately treated by current techniques include:

    * Classification of protein internal spaces and their connectedness to the outside.
    * Dynamic evolution of protein geometric properties.
    * Docking of macro-molecules to protein receptor sites. 

We have recently begun to develop new methods -- in part inspired by algorithms used in computer-aided design and visualization for calculating molecular geometric properties. These new methods apply a ray-casting formalism to the analysis of molecular structure."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>