<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Petroleum and Geosystems  Engineering Curriculum - University of Texas at Austin</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The MS program is designed to provide a rigorous yet broad graduate education in most disciplines of petroleum engineering.

The PhD program is designed to educate engineers to solve problems related to exploring and recovering subsurface resources such as oil and gas. In addition to the traditional advanced petroleum engineering areas, the program allows students to study in situ environmental cleanup and underground waste disposal. Students may specialize in computational geosystems engineering, drilling engineering, environmental and geosystems engineering, formulation evaluation, petroleum economics, production engineering, or reservoir engineering.

Students take several courses in their area of specialization and have the option of taking courses from the other areas. A list of the courses in each area is available from the graduate adviser. Once students have chosen a degree option, they may choose to work closely with a faculty member conducting research in that area. The program offers a doctoral degree based on a combination of coursework and research, and a master's degree based on either a thesis or a report, or on coursework alone.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>