<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Computer Science Curriculum - UT Austin</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The foundation of the department's graduate program is its research.  Particular areas of strength include Systems (hardware, software, and the interface between them), Artificial Intelligence and Robotics, and Formal Methods and Verification. See Research Areas for a tour through the department's research projects.

The Computer Science Department offers two graduate programs:

The Ph.D. program is designed for students who wish to pursue research careers, either in academia or in industry. There are 192 students currently pursuing their Ph.D.'s in the department.

The Masters program is designed for two groups of people:

    * Students who have bachelors degrees in CS or some related field and who want to broaden and deepen their knowledge of computer science, typically to enhance their careers in industry.
    * Students who have degrees in fields other than CS and who want to prepare themselves for computing careers. These students should read carefully Admission Material to see if they meet the background requirement for admission to the CS Masters program."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>