<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>NSF ADVANCE  Program at Skidmore - Union SUN Network</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Type:  Partnerships for Adaptation, Implementation, and Dissemination;
Year Awarded: 2008.

Description: "This project is a collaboration of Skidmore College and Union College, two small, selective liberal arts colleges located in close proximity in upstate New York, to enhance the recruitment and retention of women in the STEM disciplines and to promote their advancement through rank. The multifaceted program uses and adapts exemplary tools from NSF ADVANCE Institutional Transformation programs at large research institutions to the climate and conditions at Skidmore and Union Colleges and more broadly contributes to the adaptation, translation, development and expansion of these resources to predominately undergraduate liberal arts colleges in general. Intellectual merit. The adaptation of exemplary tools from large research institutions to Skidmore College and Union College, where the relative importance of teaching, scholarship, and service is quite different from research universities, will provide valuable models and resources for the NSF ADVANCE "Best Practices" portfolio. It should be noted that Skidmore and Union differ from one another in significant ways: Skidmore, co-educational since 1971, was originally a women's college that traditionally emphasized arts and humanities. Over the course of the past decade, it has been successful in increasing the role of the STEM disciplines in its curriculum..."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>