<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Undergraduate CS Curriculum - University of California at Berkeley</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The Berkeley EECS major, offered through the College of Engineering (COE), combines fundamentals of computer science and electrical engineering in one major. The EECS Department offers two undergraduate programs: Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE), and Computer Science and Engineering (CSE). Students working for the B.S. degree select an Option within their program and are then assigned an appropriate advisor on the basis of their selection.
 There are two different major programs in CS at Berkeley. One major leads to the Bachelor of Arts (see below) and the other, the CSE major, leads to the Bachelor of Science.

The CSE program includes Option IV (Computer Science). The Computer Science option is for students with interests in all aspects of computer science, including design and analysis of algorithms, complexity theory, artificial intelligence, computer graphics, and database systems. The transcripts of students in Option IV indicate that their degree is from the computer science and engineering program."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>