<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Education-Portal.com Rankings of Architectural Engineering Programs</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>This site provides a list of Education-Portal.com's top ranked academic programs in Architectural Engineering.
"Architectural engineers must be both creative and analytical. Students who study this field will realize that they not only have to take their ideas and turn them into reality, but they also need to apply science to theoretical designs and plans.

After a design is created, architectural engineers brainstorm on ways to erect the building so that it is structurally sound, using the right materials and the best foundations. In the field, architectural engineers oversee the construction of homes, buildings, and many other structures.

Architectural engineers are responsible for ensuring that buildings comply with fire and safety codes and other regulations set by the government. They are accountable for designing buildings that will withstand inclement weather, fire, and other such disasters. These professionals may be employed by an architectural firm, a construction company, or choose to enter a private practice."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>