<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Graduate Biomedical Engineering Curriculum - Boston University</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>|The Graduate Program in Biomedical Engineering at Boston University is one of the handful of elite programs in the country, as evidenced by the fact that we are one of only three program to receive the Whitaker Foundation's highest honor, the Leadership Award. Highlights of our program include the following:

    * The great majority of PhD students come in under fellowships, and are guaranteed full financial aid for the duration of their studies, as long as they are making satisfactory progress toward the degree.
    * Students choose their laboratory homes through a rotation system rather than being required to join a particular laboratory in their first year.
    * Our core curriculum ensures that students gain the fundamental skills they need to become world-class Biomedical Engineers. Beyond the core courses, students have the freedom to take a number of more specialized courses within their area of specialization.
    * BU BME has over 30 primary faculty, with world-class research efforts in areas including Molecular Bioengineering, Neural Engineering, Biophotonics, Biomedical Applications of Nanotechnology, and Subcellular and Systems Biomechanics.
    * Boston is America's great center of learning. Opportunities abound for students to participate in collaborative research with many of the world's greatest hospitals.
    * BU is strongly committed to interdisciplinary approaches. Applicants to the BME PhD program can also apply to one of two interdisciplinary PhD programs: BME and Biomolecular Pharmacology or Quantitative Biology and Physiology."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>