<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Taking Successful Programs to Scale and Creating Lasting Results</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Far too often in the United States, our approach to educational problems
has been to start pilot program after pilot program.While that unleashes a lot
of bright ideas, it does not lead to sustained results. Another way of putting it is,
we&#146;ve lighted a least a million pilots in this country, but we haven&#146;t ignited the
central heating system.
Today&#146;s challenges require a new kind of philanthropy &#150; a much more
entrepreneurial philanthropy &#150; that produces measurable results. Today&#146;s leaders
in the private sector want to see hard metrics that show programs are working.
Today&#146;s investors want to know that programs have sustainability and won&#146;t
disappear when the calendar changes.
We believe the National Math and Science Initiative is establishing the kind
of 21st Century paradigm for public-private partnership that has been needed.
NMSI is expanding programs with proven, quantifiable records of success and
marshalling the funding that is essential to incubate that success across the
country. In effect, NMSI serves as a holding company, providing not just financial
support, but on-going expertise to ensure that grantees grow strong enough to
stand on their own footing.
We believe that &#147;funding to scale&#148; provides the clarity and common sense
that many philanthropists and business leaders have been seeking. Funding to
scale helps ensure that their contributions will leave a lasting legacy. This paper is
designed to explain how that model of philanthropy works. I hope you will agree
that making good programs more accessible to more people is the approach our
country needs to move forward.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>