<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lom:lom xmlns:lom="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM"><lom:educational><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:description><lom:difficulty/><lom:intendedEndUserRole/><lom:interactivityLevel/><lom:interactivityType/><lom:learningResourceType/><lom:semanticDensity/><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:educational><lom:general><lom:aggregationLevel><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>2</lom:value></lom:aggregationLevel><lom:coverage><lom:string language="en-US">united-states</lom:string></lom:coverage><lom:description><lom:string language="en-US">Curricula lead to the Bachelor of Science or Bachelor of Engineering degree with licensure as a third officer (mate or engineer) for the Merchant Marine. The license, issued by the Coast Guard, opens up the full spectrum of shoreside maritime industry related jobs and civilian sea-going employment (merchant ships, offshore drilling and mineral resource recovery, research ships, etc.). Graduates are qualified to sail on oceangoing vessels, on inland waterways, on the Great Lakes, and on coastal waters, which includes tug and barge operations.
Business administration/marine transportation students complete a strong traditional core curriculum in business administration, with minor concentrations in management, international business, transportation management, and marine operations. This program is integrated into a deck license training program in which cadets study all aspects of navigation, ship handling, and nautical rules of the road. Graduates are qualified to sail as merchant marine officers or to work ashore in the various aspects of the maritime industry, including ship chartering, ship brokerage, the import/export business, port management, and transportation management.

The College also offers outstanding programs in engineering and naval architecture. Marine engineering prepares Maritime College graduates with a broad understanding of the energy and power industries. This program is offered with a Third Assistant Engineer's License. Engine license candidates get the experience of operating a live power plant aboard the training ship, a powerful combination of design engineering and hands-on technology. Naval architecture, offered with deck or engine license, teaches the design of ships and sea-based structures, with specialty concentrations in the study and design of commercial ships, small craft, naval vessels, and offshore structures. Two new B.S. degree programs in engineering (marine operations and marine electrical and electronic systems) are offered with a deck license.</lom:string></lom:description><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>81B55FF2-24CF-40AB-AC31-233BEC550DF0</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:keyword><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:keyword><lom:structure><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>hierarchical</lom:value></lom:structure><lom:title><lom:string language="en-US">Undergraduate Naval and Marine Engineering Programs at the Maritime College</lom:string></lom:title><lom:language>en-US</lom:language></lom:general><lom:lifeCycle><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:D791B1D6-74C2-46A9-9810-45CF0AEE769D
N:Maritime College, State University of New York;Naval and Marine Engineering;null;;
FN:Naval and Marine Engineering Maritime College, State University of New York
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>author</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2007-01-01</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:version><lom:string language="en-US">N/A</lom:string></lom:version></lom:lifeCycle><lom:metaMetadata><lom:contribute><lom:entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
SOURCE:http://www.smete.org
UID:B0BF444F-C039-4252-BEFF-C0B6321C7418
N:Alice Agogino;;;;
FN:Alice Agogino
ADR;TYPE=work,postal,parcel:;;5136 Etcheverry HallUniversity of California at Berkeley;Berkeley;CA;;
TEL;TYPE=work,voice:510-849-0931
TEL;TYPE=work,fax:510-849-1822
PHOTO;VALUE=uri:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/agogino_shadow.gif
URL:http://me.berkeley.edu/faculty/agogino/index.html
END:vCard</lom:entity><lom:role><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>creator</lom:value></lom:role><lom:date><lom:dateTime>2007-01-02</lom:dateTime></lom:date></lom:contribute><lom:identifier><lom:catalog>NEEDS</lom:catalog><lom:entry>81B55FF2-24CF-40AB-AC31-233BEC550DF0</lom:entry></lom:identifier><lom:language>en-US</lom:language><lom:metadataSchema>LOMv1.0</lom:metadataSchema></lom:metaMetadata><lom:rights><lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:copyrightAndOtherRestrictions><lom:cost><lom:source>LOMv1.0</lom:source><lom:value>no</lom:value></lom:cost></lom:rights><lom:technical><lom:format/><lom:installationRemarks><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:installationRemarks><lom:location>http://www.sunymaritime.edu/Academics/Undergraduate%20Programs/</lom:location><lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:string language="en-US"/></lom:otherPlatformRequirements><lom:size>0</lom:size></lom:technical></lom:lom>