<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Nanotechnology and Microsystems Option at University of British Columbia</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Option graduates will receive instruction in traditional areas of electrical engineering including circuits, controls, digital systems, communications and power. In addition participants will learn about the science and technology that lies behind current and future generations of electronic, optical and miniature mechanical systems.  Below we try to answer some questions including: "What do we mean my Nanotechnology and Microsystems?" and "What are the job prospects?

Nanotechnology is an incredibly broad field that overlaps with chemistry, physics, biology and materials science, and which is having an impact on virtually every field of science and engineering.  The nanotechnologies of primary interest in this option are current and future devices used in integrated electronic circuits.  The particular technology that electronics and computing technology will employ in the long term is not clear yet, but but what is certain is that quantum mechanical effects are already important and will soon dominate behaviour as device sizes are reduced."
Image caption:  Undergraduate Project Work: Electrical engineering students Orion Chan and Qing Gu work with lasers and microelectromechanical systems in the Optoelectronics Research Group, on their final project. Option participants have the opportunity to work in the clean room and in research laboratories.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>