<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Video: Nanotechnology is Ready for Sesame Street</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Blog with video from Wired Magazine, Feb. 25, 2009.  Excerpt from article:
"Nanotechnology will someday change the world, but in the meantime, it may shake things up on Broadway.

Dancing nanotube puppets, and grouchy nano-hating monsters, take center stage in an adorable video made students at UC Berkeley.

"We put a lot of work into making something we hoped would be accessible and enjoyable for everyone we know who doesn't spend their life studying nanoscience," says Patrick Bennett, a nanotube researcher who directed the video.

Bennett and his friends entered their project into a contest run by the American Chemical Society, and the film has been winning since it was cast into the spotlight by Boing Boing yesterday. 

Outside of academia, not many people understand nanotechnology, so the scientific organization challenged amateur filmmakers to make a clip that answers the question: What is nano? 

In this fantastic entry, Glory Liu plays the role of a teacher and explains the science of small things with rhyming verse."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>