<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Nano-Manufacturing Within SINAM - Center for Scalable and Integrated  Nano Manufacturing</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Overview of Center for Scalable and Integrated. Nano Manufacturing (SINAM). -A NSF Nano-scale Science and Engineering Center (NSEC. Presentation slides cover the systems aspects of the research being conducted at SINAM, along with educational and outreach programs. The Center is performing research in a variety of process including nanoimprinting, plasmonic lithography and controlled nanoasssembly. These processes and being integrated with the development of nano CAD systems and test beds with many functions. Key metrology aspects of the various test beds will be discussed and some early results in nanoimprinting and plasmonic lithography presented.
Educational and Outreach mission is to address a serious nanotechnology workforce crises through Middle and High School Outreach (7-12, photolithography experiments), Community College Outreach, Undergraduate Outreach (Nanomanufacturing Summer Academy), and graduate programs (Graduate Young Investigator Program, SINAM Student Leadership Council).</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>