<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Molecular Workbench: An Interface to the Molecular World</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"The Molecular Workbench (MW) software offers interactive, visual simulations that have been widely used to teach and learn science and engineering at all levels of science education. As a free, open-source and extensible modeling platform, it provides not only a powerful environment for creating interactive molecular models and performing dynamical simulations, but also an easy-to-use authoring tool for building user interfaces and writing guided activities. In addition, it is equipped with an embedded assessment system for measuring student's learning with models and simulations. All these functionalities are seamlessly integrated under a simple user interface, which makes the sum of many difficult tasks orders of magnitude easier than they used to be for educators.

With MW's versatile simulation engines, many important concepts in physics, chemistry and biology that are otherwise too abstract to understand can be visualized with dynamical and interactive simulations. Besides creating your own, you can also find some existing activities at the MOLO and MOLIT curriculum databases."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>