<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Nanocytomer: simple pre-on-a-chip seeks out hidden cancer cells</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Cancer patients, more often than not, learn to tolerate an overdose of challenges and indignities, not to mention fear and heartache, as they manage their long treatment regimens. High on the challenge list are the necessary but endless lab tests, then the interminably long, tense days waiting for results. Has the cancer metastasized, and if it has, where has it migrated, and can those cells be isolated and destroyed? Locating rare, circulating cancer cells hiding in sites distant from a tumor is still a medical impossibility. . , But in mechanical engineering professor Lydia Sohn?s Nano-Biology Lab, where she says, ?biology meets solid-state electronics,? an interdisciplinary team is fabricating a remarkably accurate, next-generation analytical device that could enable early cancer detection of rare, isolated cancer cells where a relapse has occurred. This thumb-sized pore-on-a-chip, called a nanocytometer, could boost a patient?s chances of surviving leukemia, prostate, or breast cancer?particularly where the cancer has recurred?by locating and separating isolated metastasized cancer cells. And it could bolt into the marketplace within five years." Article in Forefront Magazine at the University of California at Berkeley.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value>N/A</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>