<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Implementation of interdisciplinary group learning and peer assessment in a nanotechnology engineering course</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>Abstract: Nanotechnology is an inherently interdisciplinary field that has
generated significant scientific and engineering interest in recent
years. In an effort to convey the excitement and opportunities
surrounding this discipline to senior undergraduate students and
junior graduate students, a nanotechnology engineering course
has been developed in the Department of Materials Science and
Engineering at Northwestern University over the past two years.
This paper examines the unique challenges facing educators in
this dynamic, emerging field and describes an approach for the
design of a nanotechnology engineering course employing the
non-traditional pedagogical practices of collaborative group
learning, interdisciplinary learning, problem-based learning, and
peer assessment. Utilizing the same nanotechnology course given
the year before as a historical control, analysis of the difference
between measures of student performance and student experience
over the two years indicates that these practices are successful and
provide an educationally informed template for other newly
developed engineering courses.

&lt;citation&gt;Mark C. Hersam, Melissa Luna, Gregory Light; Implementation of interdisciplinary group learning and peer assessment in a nanotechnology engineering course; Journal of Engineering Education; 93; 1; 49-57; 2004&lt;/citation&gt;</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>