<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>NanoEngineering Group at MIT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>The Nanoengineering Group is part of the Mechanical Engineering Department at MIT. The website has links to specific research, publications, news, as well as related courses and a textbook.

"Our research is focused on nanoscale energy transport, conversion, and storage. There are fundamental differences between transport processes at the nanoscale and the macroscale due to quantum and classical size effects; for example, both classical diffusion laws and Planck's law for blackbody radiation break down in nanostructures. We explore these effects for improving energy conversion efficiency and storage density, and thermal energy transport. Examples include development of nanostructured thermoelectric materials for direct conversion between thermal and electric energy, use of nanotechnology to advance solar thermal and solar photovoltaic devices, fundamental investigation of phonon transport. Our work is interdisciplinary and combines mechanical engineering, electrical engineering, physics, and materials science."</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>