<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Center for Scalable and Integrated Nanomanufacturing (SINAM)</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>The Center for Scalable and Integrated Nanomanufacturing (SINAM) was established through the National Science Foundation's (NSF) Nano-scale Science and Engineering Centers (NSEC) program in 2002. With the vision of a new nanotechnology manufacturing paradigm combining fundamental scientific research with industrial outlook, SINAM has developed its leadership in nanomanufacturing through the collective effort of its exceptional interdisciplinary team of academic and industrial researchers from seven institutions during our Phase I operation. In our Phase II operation, the multi-institutional team effort of SINAM including The University of California at Berkeley (UCB), The University of California at Los Angeles (UCLA), Stanford University, The University of North Carolina Charlotte (UNCC), Northwestern University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) and Hewlett-Packard Laboratories, brings together a wealth of expertise in manufacturing, process systems and modeling, material synthesis, the physical sciences and applications development. In an environment dedicated to multi-disciplinary and collaborative science, in addition to a program of education for the next generation of pioneers, SINAM creates the opportunities for industrial quantum-leaps in nanotechnology.</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>