<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Attributes><Attribute><Name>title</Name><Value>Tiny "invisibility cloak" is like a magic</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>description</Name><Value>"Researchers have created a tiny "carpet cloak" that conceals objects under it from detection using light near the human-visible part of the spectrum. While the carpet itself is visible, the bulge of the object underneath it "disappears" from the view of instruments that use this near-infrared light.

These three images depict how light striking an object covered with the carpet cloak acts as if there were no object. (Image by Thomas Zentgraf)
Researchers say they're hopeful that with more precise fabrication their strategy should yield a true "invisibility carpet that works in the area of the color spectrum utilized by human eyes, and at a larger size.

The carpet works such that shining a beam of light on the bulge shows a reflection identical to that of a beam reflected from a flat surface.

"We have come up with a new solution to the problem of invisibility based on the use of dielectric [nonconducting] materials, said Xiang Zhang of the Univers
ity of California Berkeley and Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory in California, leader of the research team."

Image caption: These three images depict how light striking an object covered with the carpet cloak acts as if there were no object. (Image by Thomas Zentgraf)</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>content_language</Name><Value>en-US</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>format</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>requirement</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>other_platform_requirement</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>duration</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_type</Name><Value/></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_user_language</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>interactivity_level</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>context</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_min</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_age_range_max</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>difficulty</Name><Value>LOMv1.0</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>typical_learning_time</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_concept_and_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_skilllevel_prerequisite</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>taxon_path_idea_discipline</Name><Value>DEFAULT</Value></Attribute><Attribute><Name>intended_end_user_role</Name><Value/></Attribute></Attributes>